PROFESSOR: So the first way we're
going to speed up the basic
backtracking algorithm is with
an approach called filtering.
And filtering's really all about
ruling out suspects.
Now of course, the backtracking search
eventually tries things and finds out
whether or not they work.
Filtering is about going ahead of the
backtracking search and figuring out
elements in the domains of the
unassigned variables, which can safely
be eliminated.
So we'll see a couple different
approaches of filtering.
The first approach is called
forward checking.
And in general, whenever we're doing
filtering, we're going to have to add
one new idea in addition to this
idea of a partial assignment.
The unassigned variables now will have
their domains exposed, and we're going
to cross off bad options
as we discover them.
OK, so in forward checking, things
look like this to begin with.
We don't have anything in the partial
assignment, so nothing's assigned, but
all of the remaining unassigned
variables have their domains shown.
What we're going to do in forward
checking is every time we make an
assignment in the backtracking search,
we're going to check the unassigned
variables, and if any of their values
would be conflicting with our existing
assignment, we're going
to cross them off.
So here's the empty one.
Let's do an assignment.
Let's say we assign red
to Western Australia.
What happens?
Well, Western Australia is now going to
take on its single value red, and
so what we're going to have to do is
we're going to have to look and see,
are there any values in the domains of
the other variables that have to go?
Well, for example, is there going to be
any value in the Northern Territory
variable, NT, that has to go?
Sure.
It can't be red.
All right, so things are going to look
like this after we assign red to WA.
So WA is now assigned.
NT and SA aren't assigned, but their
remaining domains have shrunk.
Now what do we do?
Well, we assign something else.
We're still in a backtracking search.
Let's say we assign to Queensland,
we assign it to green.
OK, so Queensland will now be assigned
to green, and everything adjacent to
Queensland will have to check to see
whether or not there are now values
which are unworkable.
OK, so we're going to check everything
adjacent, and we're going to cross off
a bunch of greens.
We'll end up in this state.
OK, so we can see that for example, New
South Wales no longer has green
because it's no longer possible to
assign that without violating a
constraint against our existing
assignment at Queensland.
All right, now let's look
at this, for example.
What might we do next?
We might assigned here to Victoria,
to V here, we might assign blue.
Well, what will happen?
Well, a bunch of things are now going
to lose blue from their domain, and
we're going to end up here where
South Australia actually
has no legal values.
In terms of our assignment,
nothing's gone wrong.
We haven't actually violated any
constraints with our assignment.
But we know that as a consequence of
what we've already done, some variable
that is as yet unassigned has just
had its domain go empty.
Sooner or later we're going to get to
that variable, and then have to
backtrack, so we might as
well backtrack now.
This is the idea of filtering,
and in particular the
case of forward checking.
We cross things off as we go, and as
soon as something goes empty, we know
that no solution is possible,
and we can backtrack early.
So let's take a look at
this in the demo.
We're going to keep our
backtracking search.
We are now going to add forward checking
as filtering, and you'll
notice that as soon as we switch
into a filtering mode, we
have an extra notion.
Even though nothing's assigned, there
are still remaining domains.
So I'm going to do an assignment, and
the first assignment is going to be to
the lower left, and it's
going to assign blue.
As soon as I assign blue,
what's going to happen?
For these three variables here next to
it, blue is going to disappear from
their domain.
So there you go.
All right, so we still only
have one assignment.
We're going to move on to the next
variable in the lower center.
We're going to assign the next thing,
which in this case will be red.
And as soon as I do that, you can see
that in the adjacent variables, red
has disappeared.
I assign again.
And I sign again to green here.
Now a domain has gone empty,
and I'll have to backtrack.
So I'll backtrack a little bit.
And then I solve it.
OK.